A Guide to the Virginia Secretary of Education, Correspondence and subject files, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Secretary of Education, Correspondence and subject files, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
38994
19 cubic feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Office of the Secretary of Education January 10, 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
The secretarial system of organizing state government agencies was established by the General Assembly in 1972. The secretaries are appointed by the Governor and serve at his pleasure. Their primary mandates are to resolve conflicts among assigned agencies and officials; to direct the formulation of a comprehensive program budget for their assigned agencies; hold agency heads accountable for their administrative, fiscal and program actions; and direct the development of planning necessary for the effective and efficient operation of government. The Secretary of Education assists the Governor in the management of state agencies in the area of education, including the boards of public institutions of higher education, the community college system and various cultural institutions in the Commonwealth. The Secretary of Education also provides leadership and vision for all public education in Virginia.
Wilbert Bryant was appointed Secretary of Education by Governor Jim Gilmore on January 18, 1998. Prior to his appointment, Bryant served as Deputy Secretary of Education for former Governor George Allen.
Scope and Content Information
This collection is comprised of Wilbert Bryant's correspondence and subject files, 1998-2001, from his tenure as Virginia Secretary of Education. The collection is organized into the following series: Constituent Correspondence (15 cu. ft.); Appointment Calendars (.5 cu. ft.); Correspondence with State Agencies (1.5 cu. ft.); and Subject Files (2 cu. ft.). Subjects covered in the correspondence include prepaid tuition contracts, funding for higher education, Literacy Passport test, school vouchers, SOLs, teacher salaries, TAG, Virginia Commission for the Arts, teacher education, school violence, Blue Ribbon Commission, and many others.
Contents List
- Series I: Constituent correspondence, 1998-2001
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 93 - 25,997, 1998 February-June (Box 1)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 26,463 - 36,294, 1998 June-November (Box 2)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 36,370 - 53,495 1998 November - 1999 January (Box 2A)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 53,562 - 68,176, 1999 January-April (Box 3)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 68,206 - 82,968, 1999 April-September (Box 4)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 83,020 - 93,878, 1998 February-June (Box 5)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 93,900 - 99,247, 1999 November-December (Box 6)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 99,318 - 110,986, 2000 January-March (Box 7)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 111,068 - 2027180, 2000 March-September (Box 8)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2027236 - 2038823, 2000 September-December (Box 9)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2038825 - 2043904, 2000 December - 2001 January (Box 10)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2043907 - 2067521, 2001 January-May (Box 11)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2067535 - 2073298, 2001 May-July (Box 12)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2073300 - 2085776, 2001 June-November (Box 13)
  - Constituent correspondence, ID number 2085841 - 2088846, 2001 November-December (Box 14)
- Series II: Appointment calendars, 1998-2001
  - Appointment calendars, 1998-2001 (Box 15)
- Series III: Agency correspondence, 1998-2001
  - Blue Ribbon Commission on Higher Education, 1998-2000 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence with state agencies, 1998-2001 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence of the Secretary, 1998-2001 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence of the Deputy Chief of Staff, 1998-2001 (Box 16)
  - Local School Construction, 1998 (Box 16)
  - Governor's Commission on Local School Construction, 1998 (Box 16)
- Series IV: Subject files, 1998-2001
  - Century Date Change Initiative Project Office (Y2K), 1998-2000 (Box 17)
  - Governor's accomplishments files, 1998 (Box 18)